I don't think
this is going to reach readers.
The characters' emotions
and the sadness of the story
just aren't coming through.
Wait, have you made your debut...?
Debut...?
Right, of course, my apologies.
Mr. Satoru Fujinuma.
You need to be committing more.
I can't see the author
in the work.
Okay? Okay. Good luck.
Editor-in-chief,
sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm scared.
I'm scared to face myself.
I'm scared I'll find out that
I have nothing to offer the world.
I hear myself saying every day:
"If only I did things differently then."
They're not words of regret.
They're just excuses.
To protect myself from breaking.
We've got two new deliveries.
Fujinuma.
We have work to do.
Here you go.
-Katagiri is off for delivery.
-Okay, be careful. Here.
-I'm off, then.
-All right, be careful.
Fujinuma.
Don't eat the pizza on your way there.
I won't.
I don't get it.
Is that some millennial joke?
Could she at least say something
I could use for my manga?
Nobody has probably noticed,
but in our mundane daily routines,
there is always something happening
around every single person.
And what you pick up
is what makes a great manga author.
Oh, there I go thinking about manga again.
I'm not picking up anything.
It's happening again.
There's no mistake.
Something is going to happen again.
Something bad.
It always does.
I don't want to get involved.
But I have to find it.
What seems off?
I need to find it.
Somewhere around here.
Something bad is going to happen.
Where is it?
Find it.
Pick it out.
Found it. I found what's wrong.
Hey.
Stop.
Wake up.
Hey.
Stop.
Hey!
Stop!
Fujinuma?
Wake up, already!
Stop the truck!
Hey!
See?
I knew it.
I shouldn't have gotten involved.
Oh, you're awake.
Do you know who you are
and why you're here?
I'm Satoru Fujinuma, age 29.
I tried to save a child from a truck...
and was involved in an accident.
Thank goodness.
That was two days ago.
It's a miracle
you weren't more seriously hurt.
They'll discharge you
after you clear your examination.
Is there anyone you want to contact?
Like a friend or a girlfriend?
There isn't anyone I'd bother telling.
Snip, snip, snip.
What is that?
You seemed like you were trapped
in a cocoon or something.
You don't seem like the type
to open up to other people.
But I have new respect for you.
I was there.
The truck driver died of a heart attack
at the wheel.
How did you notice that?
Hey, Katagiri...
why do you work?
I have a dream.
And I want to make it happen
with my own money.
Aren't you ever worried about...
telling someone your dream,
and then having that dream never happen?
Nope.
I feel like... the more you say it,
the more likely it is to come true.
Well, take care.
Oh,
apparently your mother is on her way here.
Bye, then.
My mother?
So annoying.
I call that phenomenon "Revival."
I usually go back
between one and five minutes
and experience the same scene.
It's always right before
something bad is about to happen.
It's as if...
someone is forcing me
to try to prevent it.
As a result,
I've prevented countless mishaps.
Usually,
I manage to turn a negative
into something neutral.
But sometimes, like this time,
there's a witness,
and I get labeled a hero.
I didn't have to take any blame
for the accident.
Welcome home, Satoru.
How are you feeling?
This isn't the countryside.
You gotta keep the door locked.
-So, are you all right?
-Yeah.
So, I'll be staying here for a while.
-What?
-You need someone to look after you.
I'll be fine.
I've got my work and my manga.
If you can't write your manga
because your mother's here,
then you were never going
to write it anyway.
...his first victory.
In the honwari,
Miyabiyama defeated Asasekiryu,
while Hakuho was victorious
against Baruto,
leaving them even at 14 victories apiece.
In the championship match,
Hakuho avenged his earlier loss
to Miyabiyama
to be crowned Yokozuna.
Hey, Satoru.
Can you get to Ueno on one train?
No.
So, you are here to sightsee.
The 7-year-old girl Ayaka Sakamoto
missing since the 8th of the month,
has been safely found this morning.
Ayaka was admitted to a local hospital,
but appeared to be unharmed
and in good spirits.
Hey, Satoru.
Do you remember?
What?
Ayaka Sakamoto is 7 years old...
The incident that happened
in the neighborhood
when you were in fifth grade.
No.
We were all doing the best we could.
We just tried to make it easier
for you kids to forget about it.
Satoru, you were in some real danger.
When I was in fifth grade,
there was a wave
of kidnappings and murders.
JAPAN UNDERGROUND
BIG CRIMES FROM THE SHOWA PERIOD
HOKKAIDO ELEMENTARY
SERIAL KIDNAPPING MURDERS
Two out of the three victims
were from my class.
HIROMI SUGITA (11)
KAYO HINAZUKI (10)
And the suspect who was arrested
was someone I knew well.
JUN SHIRATORI ON DEATH ROW
Satoru. I bet I can guess
who's popular in your class.
What?
They're outgoing and good at sports.
Even though they joke around,
they speak their mind.
And they have one thing
that they really care about.
If you want friends,
why don't you try copying them?
Don't feel embarrassed.
Have the courage.
Courage?
Because he liked using the word yuuki,
or "courage," a lot,
I... I called him Yuuki.
Right now,
Yuuki is locked up on death row.
This is from Corporate,
for everything you've been through.
Oh, thank you.
By the way, Satoru,
don't forget that you said
you'd think about joining Corporate.
Oh, it can wait until you're ready
to move on from being a manga author.
Thank you, that's considerate.
-All right, see you tomorrow.
-Okay.
You bought way too much.
Invite some people over, then.
Like your friends or a girlfriend.
I don't have any. I only have my manga.
That's why I told you not to run.
This is what you get.
No crying. You did this yourself.
That's why I told you not to run.
I knew you would drop it.
Fujinuma.
You do have one.
Oh, please.
I have something of yours.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Invite some people over, then.
Like your friends or a girlfriend.
A Revival now?
-What is it?
-I told you not to run.
-What's about to happen?
-Why did you run, then?
Mom, would you mind taking a look around?
I'm getting a strange feeling.
What?
Wait a second.
You've said something like this before.
You were feeling uneasy about something.
Fujinuma.
I have something of yours.
-Katagiri, don't run. It's dangerous.
-What?
Fujinuma.
The manager handed me this book
to give to you, and I forgot.
Who is that?
My mother.
What?
Wow, I swear,
I thought she was your sister.
Nice to meet you. I'm Airi Katagiri.
Nice to meet you. I'm Sachiko Fujinuma.
Say, Airi...
I'm making curry tonight.
Would you like to join us for dinner?
-Yes, I'd love to.
-What?
-In that case, let's go.
-Okay. Let's go.
I knew it.
I thought you were too young
to be his girlfriend, and I was right.
That's too bad.
Satoru is like a friend I can look up to.
Is it too spicy?
It's freaking good.
It's so good.
Sure you don't need him to see you off?
Yes, I've got my bike.
Thank you so much for the meal.
Bye, then.
Look.
Don't look at her like I need a wife.
She's just a kid I work with.
You're so slow.
She's into you.
It's not like that.
By the way, this afternoon...
did you notice something
in the parking lot?
Oh, that?
It was an attempted kidnapping.
What?
I'm obviously just kidding.
Hello?
That man's eyes.
I knew them.
He looked like he knew what he was doing.
I'm sure this wasn't the first time
he's done this.
The kidnappings from 18 years ago...
They weren't over.
I have to...
tell Satoru...
I have to tell him I'm sorry.
My mother said
there was an attempted kidnapping
at that supermarket.
"I'm obviously just kidding."
She tried to play it off.
But my mother only says that
when she's telling the truth.
What changed when I rewound time
that caused the kidnapping to end
in just an attempt?
I need to ask Mom about that more.
Mom, I told you to lock the door,
for God's sake--
Hey.
This is a joke, right?
Say something.
Cut it out.
Hey.
Wake up.
Say it. "I'm obviously just joking."
You can get to Ueno on one train!
Mom!
Mr. Fujinuma. What's wrong?
What was the yelling for?
What is that?
Is that blood?
I got set up.
The killer purposefully let me chase him,
so our landlady would spot me.
As things are, I'm the primary suspect
in my mother's murder.
Not only did he commit murder,
he even prepared a fall guy.
What is this?
Does it have something to do
with the attempted kidnapping
my mother witnessed?
Damn it!
Hey, you. What are you doing there?
Come on.
Come on, Revival.
You've gotta come now.
How else am I going to save Mom?
Yo, Satoru, get up already.
We're gonna be late.
School backpack?
Showa?
SHOWA 63
(1988)
1988?
MIKOTO ELEMENTARY
Subtitle translation by
Zensho Yamamoto